Guide to the Alexander Gordon Bearn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty, Ingests, post-1990 FA1083
Rockefeller Archive Center
Alexander Gordon Bearn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty, Ingests, post-1990
1962-1988
Rockefeller Archive Center
Bearn, Alexander G., 1923-2009
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research.
Rockefeller University
FA1083
34.8 Cubic Feet 29 record storage cartons.
29 record storage cartons.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 B38-U
Arrangement note
Arranged as received.
Biographical/Historical note
Alexander G. Bearn (1923-), a physician and scientist, was affiliated with the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research starting in 1951. Prior to that he was a house physician at Guy's Hospital (1946-1947) and house physician in the Postgraduate Medical School (1948-1951), both in London. Subsequently, after joining the staff of RIMR, he was an associate professor (1957-1964) and then professor and senior physician (1964-1966). In 1966, he accepted the position of professor of medicine at Cornell University where he was the chairman of the department of medicine until 1977. During this period, he was physician-in-chief of New York Hospital.
Dr. Bearn has also served as a trustee of the Rockefeller University and the Helen Hay Whitney Foundation, a member of the board of scientific counselors of Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center and the National Institute of Arthritis, Metabolism and Digestive Diseases. Bearn also served as president of the Royal Society of Medicine Foundation, Inc.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Material documents a variety of Bearn's activities across his professional career including but not limited to: lectures, workshops, seminars, RIMR and RU committees, as well as Bearn's work at Cornell Medical Center, New York Hospital and Helen Hay Whitney Foundation.
- National Academy of Sciences, 1977-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1-14)
- National Academy of Sciences, 1982-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
- National Research Council, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 5-9)
- National Research Council, 1977-1984 (Box 3, Folder 1-12)
- American Philosophical Society, 1976-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1-4, Box 5, Folder 6-7)
- Lectures, 1981-1985 (Box 4, Folder 5-11)
- Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation, 1982-1987 (Box 4, Folder 12-13, Box 5, Folder 1-6)
- Commonwealth Fund - Book Program, 1982-1987 (Box 5, Folder 7-12, Box 6, Folder 1-5)
- Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences - Papers, 1980-1987 (Box 6, Folder 6-17, Box 7, Folder 1-5)
- Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences - Papers, 1979-1987 (Box 7, Folder 6-24, Box 8, Folder 1-9)
- Lectures, 1975-1981 (Box 8, Folder 10-29)
- Lectures, 1960-1978 (Box 9, Folder 1-19)
- Institute of Medicine, 1978-1980 (Box 10, Folder 1-14)
- Institute of Medicine, 1980-1986 (Box 11, Folder 1-14)
- National Institutes of Health, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- National Institutes of Arthritis, Metabolism and Digestive Diseases (NIAMDD), 1978-1980 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Rockefeller University - Committee Material, 1980-1987 (Box 12, Folder 1-12)
- Rockefeller University - Committee Material, 1980-1988 (Box 13, Folder 1-23)
- Rockefeller University - Committee Material, 1982-1988 (Box 14, Folder 1-19)
- Rockefeller University - Committee Material, 1972-1987 (Box 15, Folder 1-10)
- Cornell Medical Center, 1969-1987 (Box 15, Folder 11-15)
- Cornell Medical Center, 1974-1987 (Box 16, Folder 1-4)
- Genetics Lectures (Box 16, Folder 5-9)
- Cornell Medical Center - Photos, 2016:FA1083:001 (Box 2016:FA1083:001)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted from scholarly access - Material will be open following stabilization.
  Separated Materials
  Special format items (still images) have been separated from the file and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
- Cornell Medical Center - Slides, 2016:FA1083:002 (Box 2016:FA1083:002)
- Cornell Medical Center - Slides, Negatives, Presentations, 2016:FA1083:003 (Box 2016:FA1083:003)
- Cornell Medical Center - Audio Tapes, 2016:FA1083:004 (Box 2016:FA1083:004)
  Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
  Special format items (audio) have been separated from the file and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
- Cornell Medical Center (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Conferences, Symposia and Proposals, 1970-1988 (Box 16, Folder 11-16)
- Conferences and Symposia, 1970-1988 (Box 17, Folder 1-3, Folder 8-11)
- Rockefeller University - General, 1972-1988 (Box 17, Folder 4-7)
- Helen Hay Whitney Foundation, 1980-1988 (Box 17, Folder 12-16, Box 18, Folder 1-5)
- Progress in Medical Genetics, 1975-1986 (Box 18, Folder 6-17, Box 19, Folder 1-11)
- Progress in Medical Genetics, 1975-1986 (Box 20, Folder 1-8)
- Material related to papers, articles, books, journals and symposia, 1962-1986 (Box 20, Folder 9-24)
- Material related to papers, articles, books, journals and symposia, 1962-1986 (Box 21, Folder 1-21)
- Material related to papers, articles, books, journals and symposia, 1962-1986 (Box 22, Folder 1-7)
- Personal Affairs, 1970-1987 (Box 23, Folder 1-23)
- Personal Affairs - Calendars (Box 24)